My brother-in-law, Sammy, lost his home shortly after his divorce 10 months ago.
He moved in with us and brought his twin daughters, Olivia and Sloane, 18, with him a couple of
months ago. His sister, my wife, and I have one daughter, Zoe, 16, and she and her cousins aren't
close but get along fine. Olivia and Sloane have no respect for Zoe's privacy, none. They used to
walk into her room and take everything they get their hands on. Makeup, phone accessories, clothes,
school laptop, etc. Zoe complained a lot and I've already asked the girls to respect Zoe's privacy
and stop taking things. My wife and Sammy saw no issue with this. After all, they're girls and
this typical teenage girl's behavior. I completely disagreed. Last straw was when Zoe bought a $60
MAC makeup kit that looks like a paint set that she saved up for over a month and one of the girls,
Sloane took it without permission and ruined it by mixing shades together while using it.
Don't know much about makeup but that's what Zoe said when she found the kit on her bed
and was crying. I told my wife and she said she'd ask Sloane to apologize but I got Zoe a lock
after I found she was moving valuable belongings out the house because of this incident.
Sammy and his daughters saw the lock and weren't happy. The girls were extremely upset.
Sammy asked about it and I straight up told him. He said my daughters aren't thieves. It's normal
that girls of the same age borrow each other's stuff. He said Zoe could easily get another makeup
kit for $15 from Walmart and shouldn't even be buying expensive adult makeup in the first place
and suggested my wife take care of this defect in Zoe's personality trying to appear older than
she is. He accused me of being overprotective and babying Zoe with this level of enablement.
I told him this between me and my wife but she shamed me for putting a lock on Zoe's door for
her cousins to see and preventing them from spending time with her saying I was supposed
to treat them like daughters then demanded I remove it but I said this lock does not get
removed till her brother and his daughters are out of our house. She got mad I was implying we
kicked them out and said her family will hate me for this. So I reminded her that I let Sammy and
his family move in which is something her own family refused to do so she should start with
shaming blaming them for not taking their own son and nieces slash granddaughters in. If it wasn't
for her family's unwillingness to help we wouldn't be dealing with this much disturbance at home.
Everyone's been giving me and Zoe silent treatment and my wife is very much upset over this.